Sathwik Kondapuram

E-mail: sk67015@uga.edu || sathwikkondapuram@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experience of 3+ years in Front End, Databases, Big Data, Analytics and AWS. Expertise in all phases of SDLC and well versed with Agile work environment. Good at problem solving, analyzing and communication. Open to work on new technologies.

EDUCATION

University of Georgia, Athens, GA

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2021

Ph: +1 (470) 437-7322

Master's in computer science

GPA: 4

Courses: Algorithms, Data Science, Advanced Data Analysis, Computer Vision, Database Management, Advanced Database

Management, Operating Systems, Advanced System Security, Advance Cyber Security, Data warehousing

JNTU, Hyderabad

July. 2014 – May. 2018

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

GPA: 3.8

SKILLS

Programming: Java, Python, JavaScript

Database Technologies: Oracle Database (SQL), PostgreSQL, Mongo DB, Neo4j (Cypher).

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js Big Data: Apache Spark, Apache Hudi, Apache Hive

AWS: EMR, Glue, S3, EC2, VPC, IAM, Athena, SNS, SQS, Redshift, Lambda, and step functions

CI/CD: GIT, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS Code Commit and Code pipeline

WORK EXPERIENCE

Amazon

Data Engineer Intern

June. 2021 – Aug. 2021

- Designed and implemented an end-to-end solution for GDPR on S3 Datasets using Apache Hudi, AWS EMR, Glue catalog, Athena, Redshift and Dynamo DB, DMS, SNS, Apache Spark and Hive. This project enables us to execute data deletion requests in an optimal way.
- Implemented, deployed, and Tested end to end CI/CD pipeline. Due to need for data freshness once in every 7 data commits are appended with inline compaction. Using this metrics on average 90% of computation and I/O costs are saved compared to old GDPR implementation mechanism.
- Designed and drafted standards to follow for implementing deletion on datasets stored in S3 efficiently and optimally.

Carl Vinson Institute of Government

Graduate Research Assistant-Software Developer

Aug. 2020 - Current

- Work on ad-hoc requests, address the problems, create reports and dashboards using Qlik(QlikSense, Nprinting).
- Address the questions with deep dive analysis on huge amounts of data using Python, SQL, Excel and Qlik.
- Working in Agile environment, with an ability to accommodate and test the newly proposed changes at any point of time during the release using GitLab.
- Gather requirements from Georgia government and design and implement the end-to-end development. Worked on
 multiple projects involving Data Collections, Performing ETL, building analytical data source, generating visualizations
 and implementing Single Page Applications and Static web pages with different visualizations and stories.

Apps Associates

Associate Software Engineer

Aug. 2017 – Jun. 2019

- Worked on an Agile development team to deliver regular updates to business team and project managers.
- · Designing web pages using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React and Oracle APEX
- Working in Agile environment, with an ability to accommodate and test the newly proposed changes at any point of time during the release using GitLab.
- Worked on React JS Virtual Dom and React views. Implemented various screens for the front end using React.js and used various predefined components from NPM (Node Package Manager) and redux library. Implemented stable React components and stand-alone functions to be added to any future pages.
- · Used Jest and Enzyme for unit testing and eslint, sonarlint for code analysis and debugging as part of code deployment.

Links: Know more about my projects and experience @ **Profile:** https://sathwikkondapuram.netlify.app/#about **Github:** https://github.com/SathwikKondapuram

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sai-sathwik-reddy-kondapuram-64301013b/